It hurts.
هذا مؤلم
I'll be gentle.
أبي، كن لطيفاً
What can you do to me?
ماذا يمكنك أن تفعل بي
Steal vegetables at four.
سرق الخضروات في الساعة الرابعة
No one except me can ever do that.
لا أحد
I'm going to take them all!
خذها كلها
♫If you don't know where to go tomorrow♫
إذا كنت لا تعرف أين يجب أن تذهب غدا
♫Can you stay by my side and be my wife?♫
كوني زوجتي بجانبي
Shuai,
وسيم وسيم
time to come downstairs for breakfast!
لنذهب لتناول الفطور
Okay!
حسنا
No way.
لا
Wang Diqiu!
‫وانغ الأرض‬
You're so clumsy.
أنت متهور
Behave yourself. Hurry up and have breakfast.
لا تبدين مثل الطالبة تناولي الطعام بسرعة
Diqiu,
الأرض
no matter how busy you are, you have to eat breakfast!
يجب أن تأكل الفطور مهما كنت مشغولا
Well,
لا تقولي
Ting may look like a noisy girl.
لا تنظري إلى تينغ تينغ
When it comes to having a meal,
في مشكلة الأكل
she...
يجب أن يكون هذا
Wang Diqiu!
‫وانغ الأرض‬
Give me back my vegetables!
أعدي لي طعامي
You haven't eaten anything!
لم تأكل
Sit down and eat some.
اجلس وتناول
Why are you eating while running?
لماذا تركض لتناول الطعام
Why is everyone like this?
لماذا كل هذا؟
Slow down!
ببطء
I'm so worried about their stomachs.
هل يمكنك تحمل المعدة
I should have never praised her.
هذا غير معقول
Press and knead Sibai acupoint.
تدليك
One.
واحد
Two.
اثنان
Three.
ثلاثة
Four.
أربعة
Five.
خمسة
Eight.
ثمانية
Again, one.
اثنان
Three.
ثلاثة
What's wrong? Why are you so lethargic in the morning?
ما الخطب؟ لماذا أنت متوترة في الصباح الباكر؟
Nothing.
لا شيء
Eight.
ثمانية
Again, one.
ثلاثة
If
إذا
your mom
أمك
has a new boyfriend,
لديها حبيب جديد فجأة
what would you do?
ماذا ستفعل
Seven.
سبعة
Eight.
ثمانية
Again, one.
أربعة
Two.
اثنان
If my dad finds out he's cheated,
إذا عرف أبي أنه يرتدي قبعة أخضر
he'll be crying all the time.
سيغسل وجهه بكاء كل يوم
Seven.
سبعة
Does Ms. Jin have a new boyfriend?
السيدة جين لديها حبيب جديد
Again, one.
خمسة
Two.
اثنان
I don't know.
لا أعرف
You can't expect them to be single forever.
لا يمكن الاعتماد عليهم طوال حياتهم
I know you're right.
هذا صحيح
But now I want to know
ولكن الآن أريد أن أعرف
who my mom's new boyfriend is.
من هي حبيبة أمي الجديدة
Three.
ثلاثة
Four.
أربعة
Your mom's boyfriend, right?
رجل أمي أليس كذلك
It's okay.
لا بأس
I'll help you with it.
دعني أساعدك
In my opinion...
برأيي
What's your opinion?
ما رأيك؟
Tell me about it.
أخبرني
Mr. Yang.
سيدة يانغ
You don't want a pair of healthy eyes?
لا تريد العين
Eight.
‫ثمانية‬
Two.
اثنان
Three.
ثلاثة
Four.
أربعة
Good girl,
موهبة جيدة
that's all for today.
هذا كل شيء
Let's continue the class next Saturday.
حسناً لنواصل يوم السبت القادم
Okay.
حسنا
Thank you, Ms. Lu.
شكراً لك سيد لو
Goodbye, Ms. Lu.
مع السلامة يا أستاذ لو
Bye.
مع السلامة
Wei Xing! Wei Xing!
‫وي شينغ  وي شينغ
Why are you here?
لماذا أنتم هنا؟
Come on. There's something very important.
بسرعة هناك أمر مهم جدا
It's very urgent.
عاجل جدا
Is there a task ordered by the school on the weekend?
ما المهمة في عطلة نهاية الأسبوع؟
It's not about the school
ليس الجامعة
but about his mom's boyfriend.
إنه حبيب أمه
Yes.
نعم نعم
Ting, what are you talking about?
تينج تينج لماذا توبخينني
No, this is a matter of some urgency!
‫لا لقد فات الأوان
Hurry up! Let's go.
اذهب بسرعة
Wait.
انتظر انتظر
I can't wear this.
لا يمكنني ارتداء هذا
I'll go get changed.
سأغير ملابسي
I'll go with you. Hurry up.
سأذهب معك
Who moved my computer away?
من نقل حاسوبي
It must be Aunt.
لا بد أنها عمة
After all, you shouldn't have stolen my vegetables.
من طلب منك أن تسرق طعامي
Diqiu,
الأرض
I extend my condolences to you.
لا تحزني
Let's get down to business.
نعود إلى الموضوع
I can't do the task.
لا يمكنني فعل هذه المهمة
It's too tiring.
أنا متعب جدا
I wasted my great weekend on it for nothing.
هذا عطلة نهاية جيدة هباء
I knew it!
عرفت
The target is moving. Keep up.
تحركوا الهدف اتبعوني
Wait, wait.
انتظر انتظر
We shouldn't do this.
هذا ليس جيدًا
Yeah.
نعم
We can't alert her.
احذر من ضرب العشب لتنبهه
I don't care. Let's go!
لا تهتمي كثيرا لنذهب
Go. Go. Go.
هيا هيا هيا
Wait, wait. I'm getting a cramp!
‫انتظر انتظر  أنا تتشنق
Why are you dropping the ball at this critical moment?
‫لماذا تتراجع في اللحظات الحاسمة
How much is the fish?
ما سعر هذا السمك
5.8 yuan.
5.8 يوان
I'm your regular customer. Can't you give me a discount?
كلنا زبائن قديمين، اعتنوا بأنفسكم
It's a unified price in the entire market.
هذا السعر كله في السوق
Okay, I'll go over there.
حسنًا سأذهب إلى هناك لأرى
Do you want to buy cosmetics?
هل تريدون شراء مستحضرات التجميل
We have a special offer in our store today.
لدينا نشاط اليوم
-We have a free makeup experience. -No need, thanks.
هناك تجربة تصميم مكياج مجاني
Why is it a woman?
لماذا هي فتاة
It shouldn't be.
لا يمكن
Ms. Jin likes women?
العمة جين تحب النساء
How is that possible?
كيف يمكن ذلك
Otherwise, I wouldn't have been born.
كيف أتيت إذا كانت أمي تحب النساء
Is there a mistake?
خطأ
I'm not sure.
لست متأكدة
Let's wait and see.
انظر مرة أخرى
are you sure Ms. Jin really has a new boyfriend?
هل أنت متأكد أن السيدة جين لديها حبيبة جديدة
She seems to be living a colorful life.
أرى أنها تعيش حياة سعيدة
She doesn't have time to date.
ليس لديها وقت للوقوع في الحب
But how do you explain
لكن
the Men's Boxer?
كيف تفسر ملابس الرجل الداخلية الرابعة
Actually,
في الواقع
Ms. Jin and Mr. Han have been apart for so many years.
لقد انفصلت العمة جين وعم هان لسنوات عديدة
Even if she has found another one to date,
حتى لو وجدت شخص آخر
we have no right to interfere in it.
لا يمكننا التدخل
Han Shuai,
القائد هان
you have to be open-minded in terms of it.
يجب أن تفكر في الأمر
According to research,
حسب البحث
the average lifespan
عمر المتوسط
of divorcees
عمره متوسط
is five to eight years shorter than those with spouses.
أقل من الزوج خمس أو ثماني سنوات
In that case, it seems
لذلك يبدو
that it's good for her health.
هذا مفيد لصحتك
Are you sure it's not some fake news from a tabloid?
أي صحيفة صغيرة هذه الأخبار المزيفة
In my view,
في رأيي
a divorcee without any fights
لا تتشاجر بعد الطلاق
can live longer.
يجب أن تعيش أطول
That also makes sense.
هذا منطقي
Things between adults are so complicated.
أنت مزعج جدا
My mom.
يا إلهي
My dad.
أبي
My home.
منزلي
Wait! Wait!
انتظر انتظر
Guo Ting, you don't want a niece anymore, do you?
قوه تينغ هل لا تريد ابن أخي
Guo Ting!
قوه تينغ
Class begins.
حان وقت الدرس
Diqiu,
‫الأرض‬
don't play such dangerous games in the classroom.
لا تفعل مثل هذه اللعبة الخطرة في الفصل
I have an announcement before class.
‏أعلن شيئاً قبل الصف‏
The school
المدرسة
has set up night self-learning classes for senior three students.
‏في المدرسة الثانوية‏
You'd better hurry up and eat dinner after school.
‏تناولي العشاء بعد المدرسة‏
We'll meet in the classroom at 7 p.m.
اجتمعوا في الصف في الساعة السابعة
Stop complaining.
ماذا؟
You're senior three students.
في الثانوية
You know what to do.
يجب أن تعرف
Take out your compulsory textbook 4.
يجب أن أصلح أربعة
Page 36.
الصفحة 36
Lyrics to Remembering Your Charm (Remembrance of the Tale of the Crimson Cliff).
نيان نو جياو شي بي hoài cổ
The great gushing Yangtze with piling waves flows towards the east...
♫ الأمواج في الشرق ♫
It's a good chance.
فرصة جيدة
Away it carries gallant souls of the remote bygone days.
رجل رومانسي
Read aloud!
أين القوة
Stop thinking about the night self-learning classes.
لا تفكر في دراسة ليلية
Read the lyrics first.
اقرأها أولا
Focus on the moment.
أعيش في الوقت الحالي
Try it again.
مرة أخرى
The great gushing Yangtze with piling waves flows towards the east...
♫ الأمواج في الشرق ♫
Night self-learning classes.
دراسة ليلية
What do you mean?
ماذا تعني؟
Look at you.
أنت غبي
You've frowned lately.
تبدو حزينًا مؤخرًا
Let's go out and have some fun.
دعونا نخرج للاسترخاء
Have some fun?
استرخي
Here come some fruits.
الفاكهة قادمة بعد الغداء
Here.
هيا
Mom, the grapes are very sweet.
ملمس أمي حلو جدا
You are so insensitive.
ليس لديك نظرة
Just sit here.
اجلسي هنا
Grandma, do you want some kiwi fruits?
جدتي هل تأكلين الكرز؟
No. You should eat some.
‫لا آكل أنتم تأكلون‬
Poor kid.
هذا الطفل مسكين جدا
I wonder if the factory
لا أعرف إذا كان المصنع
can organize another donation.
في المصنع
If there is another donation,
إذا كان هناك
I'll help the people in the disaster area.
سأبذل قصارى جهدي من أجل مواطني في المنطقة الكارثة
I'll donate my pension later.
سأتبرع بالمال الرعاية
OK.
حسنا
Mom, stop messing around with him.
‫أمي، لا تثيري المشاكل
In the donation the factory organized last time,
في المرة السابقة تبرع في المصنع
the head of the workshop donated 500 yuan.
‫تبرع مدير ورشة السيارة خمسمائة
He, instead, donated 1,000 yuan.
لكنه دفع ألف يوان
He's stingy.
أنت بخيل جدا
How generous you are!
أنت كريم
Stop.
توقفوا
I'm going to announce something very important.
أريد أن أعلن أمرا مهما جدا
Starting from tomorrow night,
من ليلة الغد
I won't come back for dinner.
لن أعود لتناول العشاء
I'm going to night self-learning classes at school.
سأذهب إلى المدرسة للدراسة الليلية
Really?
حقاً؟
It's true.
حقا
It's good to hear.
هذا أمر جيد
It means our Diqiu
هذا يعني أن الأرض
takes the initiative to pursue progress.
تطالب بالتقدم
-Right? -You do know me well, Grandma.
أليس كذلك
Don't just have fun behind our backs.
لا تلعب سرا
I won't.
لا
He might be up to something.
لا أعرف ما الذي يخطط له
Diqiu,
الأرض
will there be any teacher
الدراسة الليلية
to keep an eye on you guys?
هل هناك معلم يتبعني؟
Of course, my teacher will be there during the classes.
طبعا المعلم موجود طوال الرحلة
He can answer questions
إذا واجهت مشكلة لا تستطيع
if we encounter difficulties.
لا يزال بإمكاني الإجابة
I'm a senior three student.
أنا في الثانوية
I used to be naughty.
كنت شقية
But now,
لكن الآن
it's time to be responsible for myself.
قد حان الوقت لتكون مسؤولا عن نفسك
Don't worry.
اطمئنوا
If you make a loud noise like this,
‏إن كنتم تثيرون المشاكل‏
you might as well go home directly after school.
من الأفضل أن تنتهي من الدراسة الليلية
Seize your time.
الوقت خاص بك
You're senior three students.
في الثانوية
Guo Ting,
قوه تينغ
where are Wang Huanyu and his friends?
‫أين وانغ تشى يو
Well...
ذلك
Okay, I got it.
حسنًا فهمت
Thank you.
شكرا
Go on with your self-study.
استمروا في الدراسة
Brothers, feel free to fight one-on-one.
إذا كنا إخوة، تعال للقتال
I'm good at sniper rifles.
أنا ماهر في لعب القناص
Be careful.
كن حذرا
I can completely defeat you even with one hand.
هل يمكنك معاملتك بيد واحدة؟
You two are so arrogant.
أنتما متغطرسان جدا
Come on.
هيا
Someone's destroyed ahead. Kill him with one shot.
هناك مسدس كبير في الأمام
I'm coming.
أنا قادم
I didn't expect
لم أتوقع ذلك
this guy to be quite skilled at shooting.
هذا الرجل ماهر في إطلاق النار
A coincidence.
بالصدفة
It must be.
لا بد أنها صدفة
How arrogant he is!
متغطرس
Doesn't he know the best sniper
هل تعرف ما هو
in the Universe Street?
هو أفضل قناص في شارع الكون
Awesome.
رائع رائع
OK.
حسنا
We won.
فزت
One Meter Sunlight?
‫متر من الشمس‬
Such a non-mainstream name.
غير رئيسي
Ignore him. Let's continue.
سنتجاهله
He's crossing the line. What should I do?
‫ماذا لو كان هذا الفتى فخوراً
Defeat him!
اقتله
Tell me
تكلم
how you want to compete with me.
كيف؟
What a coincidence.
أليست هذه صدفة
He's good at it.
مهاراته الجسدية جيدة
Who is he?
ما هو أصله
Looks like he can see through me.
أشعر وكأنه فتح الأنظار
Interesting.
مثير للاهتمام
It's so boring.
ما معنى هذا
Look.
انظر
He knows I'm not myself today.
أعلم أنني لا أستطيع
He's afraid. He's a coward.
لا أجرؤ على ذلك
I'm not afraid.
أجرؤ
Go downstairs.
انزل
You're so amazing.
رائع
At this critical time,
في هذا الوقت
you even played games in an internet cafe!
ما زلت تتسلل إلى مقهى الإنترنت للعب الألعاب
Who would have thought
من كان يتوقع
of meeting you here?
أن أقابلك هنا
You mean you can come here if you don't meet me?
يمكنك القدوم إلى هنا إذا لم تقابلني
How many times have I told you?
كم مرة قلت لك
You're senior three students.
‏في الثانوية‏
You should study hard for another year to get into a good university.
يجب أن تدرسوا سنة أخرى وتدخلوا الجامعة الجيدة
Don't you understand?
ألا تفهمون
Can you play games
ما المشكلة في لعب الألعاب
to make a living?
هل يمكن أن يكون الطعام
Can you play games for your lifetime?
يمكن أن تلعب مدى الحياة
Actually, according to my research,
في الواقع حسب دراستي
E-sports is very likely to...
من المحتمل أن يكون هذا الفيديو الإلكتروني بعد ذلك
Shut up!
اخرس
Each of you will hand over a letter of self-criticism to me tomorrow.
‏كل واحد منكما تقريراً غداً‏
Go back to your night self-learning class mow.
الآن عد إلى الدراسة الليلية
Move! Don't you understand?
لا أستطيع الصراخ، أليس كذلك؟
Yes, sir.
أستاذ
I understand.
فهمت فهمت
Why don't you trust me?
لماذا لا تصدقني
There must be no problem with the goods.
لا مشكلة في هذه البضاعة
Okay. Okay. Okay.
حسنا حسنا
Fine.
حسنا
Bye for now.
هذا كل شيء
Okay. Okay.
حسنا حسنا
Dad,
أبي
have you reached Mom
هل
recently?
هل تواصلت مع أمي؟
Why do you ask?
لماذا تسأل هذا فجأة
I'm just asking.
لا، أنا فقط أسأل
It's time for animals to reproduce.
إنه موسم ازدهار الحيوانات مرة أخرى
The air in mountains and forests
في الهواء في الغابة
is filled with hormones...
مليء بالهورمن
Dad,
أبي
I mean if...
إذا
Zhao.
الأخ تشاو
Don't mention it.
لا كلفة بيننا
Dinner?
تناول الطعام
Forget it.
لا بأس
We're close friends.
ماذا
I understand.
فهمت فهمت
Is it
نعم
the one at the end of the Jiefang West Road, right?
على رأس طريق جيه فانغ الغربي أليس كذلك
Okay.
حسنا حسنا
Wait for me.
انتظرني
I'll be right there.
سآتي حالاً
Are you going out again?
هل ستخرجين مرة أخرى؟
By the way,
صحيح
you take care of your own dinner.
سأحل العشاء بنفسي
Eat it.
كلي
The roasted meat is really tender. Try it.
اللحم المشوي ناعم جداً تذوقيه
What's wrong?
ما الخطب؟
Diqiu,
الأرض
I envy you sometimes.
أنا أحسدك أحيانا
Do your mom and dad still need a son?
هل ينقصك ابنا
Why don't they adopt me?
ما رأيك أن تتركني
I'll be renamed
سأدعوك
Wang Shuai.
وانغ سي
I think
في رأيي
you just don't know how lucky you are.
أنت محظوظ
I want a dad
أنا أريد أباً
who can buy me anything.
الذي يمكنه شراء كل شيء لي
It's pointless to be rich.
ما فائدة المال
I'm alone when I come back home every day,
كل يوم أعود إلى المنزل
just like an orphan.
مثل يتيم
My home is instead lively.
إن بيتي ليس بارداً
There are my mom
واحدة أمي
and
واحد
Guo Ting.
قوه تينغ
My head is going to explode.
رأسي ينفجر كل يوم
Well,
أخبريني
if my mom has a new boyfriend,
إذا كانت أمي لديها حبيبة جديدة
will she ignore me and my dad forever?
هل ستتجاهلني وأبي مرة أخرى
What are you thinking?
بماذا تفكر؟
After all, you are her son.
بعد كل شيء أنت ابنها
Besides, we've done so many investigations.
‫ألم نحقق كثيرا من قبل
There is no sign of her having a new boyfriend.
ألا يوجد أدلة
In my opinion,
في رأيي
you're too sensitive.
أنت تفكر كثيرا
Eat it.
كلي بسرعة
Or Ms. Jin will scold you if it's not eaten up.
‫إذا لم تنتهي الخالة جين ستوبخك بعد قليل‬
Is it reliable?
هل الأخبار موثوقة
Absolutely.
نعم
The PE class on Wednesday will be turned into a self-learning class.
‏ستغير صف الرياضة يوم الأربعاء إلى صف الدراسة‏
Our PE classes
في الأصل صفنا الرياضي
are already less than other grades.
أقل من الصف الآخر
It's...
هو الآن
It's so annoying!
هل ما زال يريد أن يعيش؟
No.
لا
We can't allow this to happen.
لا يمكننا أن نسمح لأي شخص أن يقتلنا
Do you have any good ideas?
هل لديك أي فكرة جيدة؟
We need to find our teacher and talk to him.
يجب أن نسعى إلى معلمنا
You're right.
أنت على حق
For the sake of the interests of the class, I'll absolutely support you!
‫من أجل مصالح جماعية  أدعمك بالتأكيد
Yi.
‫الأخ الأول
I agree.
‫موافق موافق
You brat.
أنت
Challenge Letter?
رسالة التحدي
It's about their PE classes.
‏عن صف الرياضة‏
The students in Class 4 have a lot of complaints.
‏الطلاب في الصف الرابع لديهم رأي كبير‏
They insist on playing basketball against teachers.
‏يجب أن يلعب مباراة كرة السلة مع الأستاذ‏
They said we should keep PE classes if they win.
‏أعطيهم درس الرياضة إن فزت‏
What do you think?
ما رأيك؟
I think it's rare for them
أعتقد أن الأولاد لديهم هذه الشجاعة
to have such courage.
من النادر الحصول على هذه الشجاعة
Brothers, come on. We should get prepared.
استعدوا جميعًا مؤخرًا
Step up our efforts to practice shooting at the basket
يجب أن نتدرب على رمي السلة
or dribble breakthrough by working in pairs.
يجب أن نتدرب
Have they accepted the challenge?
هل نجحت؟
I'll take all the credit.
لا ترى من نظم هذا
How about this?
هكذا
By then,
عندما يحين الوقت
I'll be responsible for ball handling and Han Shuai for scores.
سأتحمل المسؤولية عن السيطرة على الكرة. أنت مسؤول عن الحصول على النقاط.
-Zijun, you… -Are we really going to compete with the teachers?
زي جون، أنت
Pull yourselves together.
‫لماذا كل واحد تلو الآخر مكتئبون‬
Weren't you all excited about it
عندما تناقشتم
when we were discussing it?
ألم تكن متحمسًا جدًا؟
Let me make it clear.
دعني أعلن
I'm not a coward.
‏لست جباناً‏
But we are senior three students.
لكننا في الصف الثالث الآن
If we keep going against teachers,
‏سنكون ضد الأستاذ‏
is it...
أليس كذلك
Zheng Kai, what about you?
ماذا عنك؟
I'm not afraid of going against the teachers.
لا أخاف أن أتشاجر مع المعلم
I sprained my leg a few days ago.
السبب الرئيسي هو أنني لويت ساقي قبل يومين
I...
أنا
I don't want to be a drag on you.
أخشى أن يؤخر الأمر
It still hurts.
‫ما زلت أتألم
Yi.
‫الأخ الأول
I don't understand.
‫لا أنا لا أفهم
It's a hard-to-get opportunity.
لم يكن من السهل أن أحصل على فرصة
But why do you all become deserters?
لماذا كلهم يهربون في المعركة؟
I thought you were my brothers!
لقد عاملتكم كأخي
It's just a PE class.
مجرد درس رياضي
Stop making excuses. Coward.
‏أنت جبان‏
Who are you calling a coward?
من هو جبان
I'm saying you're a coward.
قلت إنك جبان
Pardon me?
من هو جبان؟
Shi Wenke,
شي وين كو
since you helped us a lot,
أنت تساعدنا كثيراً
will Ms. Chen invite you to her office?
هل سيدعوك السيد تشين لشرب الشاي؟
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
I have a great academic performance.
على أي حال أدائي جيد
I won't get a serious scolding.
لن أوبخ بشدة
But the most important thing now
لكن أهم شيء الآن هو
is that there are only three of us.
نحن الثلاثة فقط
It's not enough.
عدد الناس غير كافية
Yeah.
نعم
Let's see if we can persuade one or two to join us.
‫لنرى إذا كان بإمكاننا إيجاد طريقة لإحضار واحد أو اثنين‬
Do you know?
‫هل تعرف‬
Harden has a serious record of asthma.
‫كان هناك تاريخ ربو خطير في هارين‬
But now,
لكن الآن
he's the best player in the Pacific Ocean.
أفضل لاعب في تايبينغ يانغ
He even has the chance to join the Oklahoma City Thunder.
لا يزال هناك أمل للانضمام إلى فريق "لي تينغ"
No basketball player doesn't want to play basketball on the court,
لا يوجد لاعب لا يريد اللعب
as long as
الشرط هو
he really loves basketball.
إنه يحب كرة السلة حقا
Stop practicing shooting at the basket.
لماذا رمي السلة
You should hurry up and practice your collaboration.
أسرعوا في التدرب على التعاون
Count me in!
وأنا أيضاً
What's going on?
‫ماذا حدث
Yi was bribed by me.
‫لقد اشتريت الأخ الأول
Zheng Kai was convinced by me.
‫لقد أقنعت تشنغ كاي
Great job!
أحسنت
What are you waiting for?
ماذا تنتظر
Tell us what to do!
يا قائد
Well,
هكذا
Zheng Kai, you're tall,
تشنغ كاي طويل
and you take the center.
يجب أن تتحمل مسؤولية المنصب
There must be someone under the basket.
يجب أن تضمن تحت السلة
Come on.
‫اعمل بجد‬
Don't worry about anything on the basketball court.
لا تقلق في الملعب
Don't worry, Yang.
لا تقلق يا يانغ
We won't let you win.
لن نتساهل معك
There are two rounds in this 24 minutes-long game.
اللعب اليوم لمدة 24 دقيقة.
The team that scores more
أي فريق سيحصل على أكثر نقاط في الوقت المحدد
will win.
سيكون الفائز
Are you ready?
هل أنتم مستعدون؟
Yes.
‫نعم‬
Seems that our teachers are competitive.
‫يبدو المدربين قويين جدا‬
Can Wang's team win?
‫هل لا يستطيع لاو وانغ‬
It's okay.
لا بأس
It's not over yet.
لم ننتهي بعد
Come on, Diqiu!
حظ موفق، الأرض
Han Shuai, come on!
حظ موفق يا سيد هان
It's okay.
لا بأس لا بأس
Well done.
أحسنت
Good job.
أحسنت أحسنت
Let's work harder.
اجتهدوا
Here, have some water.
هيا اشربي بعض الماء
Thank you, Ting.
شكرا يا تينغ تينغ
Okay, Ting.
حسنا تينغ تينغ
Diqiu,
الأرض
fighting.
هيا
Wei Xing,
‫وي شينغ‬
thank you.
شكرا
We can definitely win.
سنفوز بالتأكيد
Although we fell behind,
رغم أن النتيجة متخلفة
the gap is not that huge.
لكن لحسن الحظ أن الفرق ليست كبيرة
Let's seize the time to catch up with them.
نحن نستغل الفرصة للهجوم
We'll win if we take it seriously.
سنفوز بالتأكيد
Come on!
هيا
Come on. Three.
هيا ثلاثة
Two.
اثنان
One.
واحد
Come on!
هيا
Go! Go! Go!
شد حيلك شد حيلك شد حيلك
Diqiu, come on!
!الأرض، تشجعي
We won!
فزت فزت
Yang,
،يانج
what happened just now...
تلك الكرة
You guys did a good job.
أنتم ممتازون
When it comes to playing basketball against us teachers,
‏لنلعب كرة السلة‏
you became relentless people.
‫أنت قاسي جداً على المعلمة
So, now Director Jiang and the teachers have decided
‫لذا قررت المدير جيانغ والمعلم
to admit defeat
‫أن تعترف بالهزيمة
and return your PE classes to you.
إعادة الرياضة للبشر
There are two more classes before the PE class.
ما زال هناك درسان هو درس رياضي
Refrain yourselves, okay?
‏سنبدأ الآن‏
Although we're in a key class,
‏رغم أن صفنا في صف مهم‏
if you want to take a PE class,
‏لكن إن أردنا كسب صف الرياضة‏
please raise your hand.
ارفع يديك للتسجيل
I'll count the number.
سأحسب عدد الناس
Why did you all put your hands down?
لماذا تركتم كل شيء؟
You don't want to take a PE class?
ألا تريدون الذهاب إلى صف الرياضة؟
Fine.
حسناً
Come on.
هيا
Let's continue with this question.
استمر في هذا السؤال
Did you see my three-point shot?
‏هل رأيتم نقاط اليوم؟‏
Was it cool?
هل أنا وسيم جدا
You've talked about it a million times.
لقد قلت ذلك 800 مرة
So annoying.
مزعج
You're so noisy!
مزعج جدا
No.
لا
It's classic, you know?
هذا يسمى كلاسيكية دائمًا، هل تفهمون؟
Qiu,
الكرة
you've also said it a million times.
هذه الجملة 800 مرة
Was someone talking just now?
هل كان أحد يتحدث للتو؟
You don't understand.
أنتم لا تفهمون
It really matters.
هذا يكفي
Did you see how I played it against Yang?
ألم ترى أنني ألعب لاو يانغ اليوم
He didn't even dare to dribble the ball.
لا يجرؤ على نقل الكرة
I snatched him off with my quick moves.
لقد كسرته
Cool! Cool!
وسيم وسيم
I'll send him back now.
سأرسله الآن
Wei Xing, see you!
‫وي شينغ إلى اللقاء
See you tomorrow!
أراك غدا
Let's go.
هيا بنا
It's Dad's.
أبي
Tell me if you have anything to say.
قل بسرعة
I'm busy right now.
أنا مشغول
Well,
أنا
I came here today
جئت اليوم أريد
to tell you
أقول لك
I was really drunk that day.
لقد شربت كثيرا في ذلك اليوم
I'm sorry.
آسف
You just came here to say that?
أنت هنا لتقول هذا
I...
أنا
No.
لا
I want to tell you
أريد أن أخبرك بما
since we did it,
بما أننا
why don't we take this opportunity
من الأفضل أن نستغل هذه الفرصة
to make things clear,
في المستقبل
Make things clear?
شرح
What do you mean?
ما هذا؟
I slept with you.
سأنام عليك
So what?
ماذا
Do you want me to apologize to you?
هل تريدني أن أعتذر لك؟
How could I
كيف يمكن
let you apologize to me?
أن تعتذري لي
I should...
يجب أن
I...
أنا أنا
Shuai.
وسيم وسيم
I finally figured it out.
فهمت
Are you two back together again?
هل أعدتما الحب القديم مرة أخرى؟
No, no, no!
لا لا
Your dad was drunk that day.
والدك ثمل في ذلك اليوم
It has nothing to do with me.
لا علاقة لي به
You know what?
هل تعرفان
These days,
هذه الأيام
I've suffered a lot
كم عانيت
because of this stupid boxer!
عانيت كثيرا
Why did you
يا لك من طفلة
bring it here?
لماذا تأخذها
Put it away. Hurry up.
‫بسرعة بسرعة احتفظي بها
Put it away.
بسرعة
Since they want to get back together,
بما أننا سنعود معاً
they can just admit it.
يجب أن تكون كريما
They are my parents.
إنه أبي وأمي البيولوجيين
Why do they have to be like this?
لماذا يجب أن أخفي
Things between adults
عالم الكبار
are usually complicated.
معقدة دائما
You should give them some time and space.
يجب أن تعطيهم بعض الوقت والمكان
They are complicated.
إنهم معقدون
I feel more complicated than they do.
قلبي أكثر تعقيدا منهم
They got divorced when I was eight.
لقد طلقوا عندما كنت في الثامنة من عمري
Did they ever consider my feelings?
هل فكرت في مشاعري
If it weren't for you,
لولاك
I would have been thrown
إذا لم تكن موجودا
into the youth detention center.
دخلت مركز المراعات الصغيرة
Here you go again.
أنت مرة أخرى
I know I'm charming.
أعلم أن أخوك ساحر
But don't fall for me.
لكن لا تقعي في حبي
Tonight,
الليلة
we'll eat
لا نركض
as much as we can.
لن أعود
Okay.
حسنا
Son,
بني
you're lucky today.
حظك جيد اليوم
I made you your favorite braised noodles.
طبخت أمك المعكرونة المطبوخة المفضلة لديك
-Thank you, Mom. -Eat it while it's hot.
شكرا أمي
Why did you use hair gel?
أنت طفلة لماذا ترسمين الشعائر
Stop learning such a thing from your dad.
تتعلم هذا من والدك
When you get older,
أقول لك عندما تكبر في السن
your hair will be in danger.
هذا الشعر سيكون خطيرا
I know.
فهمت
What's wrong?
ماذا حدث
Are you still angry
هل ما زلت غاضبة
about what happened before?
بسبب ما حدث في الماضي
No.
لا
Really?
حقا لا
We don't have a secret between us.
نحن لا نخفي شيئًا
I've thought about it these days.
لقد فكرت في هذين اليومين
I don't understand what's going on
لا أفهم
And I don't want to get involved.
لا أريد أن أتدخل
After so many years,
لقد مرت سنوات عديدة
you and Dad
أنت وأبي
have never thought about getting remarried.
لم تفكري في العودة للزواج
I know you're doing this for my own good.
أعلم أنكم جميعا من أجل مصلحتي
If that's the case,
إذا كان الأمر كذلك
I...
أنا
I shouldn't act immaturely.
غير ناضج
Or I'm not qualified to be your son.
ابنك غير إنساني
You've grown up.
لقد كبر ابني
You do have a thorough understanding of me.
أنت تفكر مليا
Alright, Mom.
حسنا أمي
Stop being like this.
لا تكوني سخيفة
I'm going to school after I finish it.
سأذهب إلى المدرسة
Okay.
حسنا حسنا
My son is the best one in the world.
‫لا يهم كيف تنظر إلى ابني‬
Why do you keep staring at Du Mingwei?
‫لماذا تراقب دو مينغ وي دائما‬
I just think he's weird.
‫أعتقد أنه غريب‬